in this Tasker session I'm going to show
you how you can take screenshots in
Tosca and I'm going to show you two ways
of doing that in one way where you can
take a screenshot anytime within your
test case it is a particular
key box module through which you can
take this particular screenshot at any
point as a test step right and then I'm
going to show you how you can capture
screenshots during execution only when
your execution fails okay so both the
ways are useful on their own methods but
so both the ways you can use in order to
take screenshots at different intervals
either only during failures or if you
want to have screenshots for any
particular step or all the steps you can
always implement this in your test cases
okay
so let's go ahead and look how we can do
this right so for this I have created
another test case folder uh screenshots
and uh I'm using our earlier test case
which we had used for this demo webshop
to log in right the only difference is
this time I'm using uh invalid
credential to login and it is going to
fail right
okay so here you can see this is the
test case with all the test steps like
opening URL uh and then clicking on
login uh entering the credentials this
time I'm using uh invalid login and then
verifying the login and then log out
right but it is going to fail in the
login step itself now we'll see how we
can capture uh this failure of this
particular test case in a cap in a
screenshot and store it somewhere right
but before that let me tell you how you
can use a t-box module to capture a
screenshot at any point in your test
case Okay so again let's search for
t-box screenshot okay so it is t-box
take screenshot that's the module name
and here you can choose an environment
either you can choose a desktop or even
a mobile okay so since we'll be working
with desktop I will choose desktop and
then uh we can choose a particular
directory where this will be stored okay
so let me choose a directory for this
and it will be this okay
and now file name
now if you notice if I give a file name
like a screenshot one
every time it is going to uh
every time it will try to rewrite this
particular screenshot one because the
name would still be same so if I run
this test case multiple times it is
going to overwrite this particular
screenshot right but what if I want to
store this all the screenshots which it
is taking in different executions right
so that can be done you just need to
apply some Dynamic expression here so
after screenshot what you can do uh you
can put some Dynamic expression and I
can
use
date time expression here so uh it will
always be unique because it will be like
it will put the date and then the time
in in terms of minutes seconds hours so
it will always be unique right it cannot
be the same file name whenever you are
using this kind of a dynamic file name
right so now I can have multiple file
names uh with different names right
which contains screenshots of each
execution
okay so what I'm going to do I'm going
to put this after uh we click on login
okay this might not be useful if my
login is failing
um because if I put it after the login
uh it probably won't get executed right
because it will fail at the login step
so let me put it before that so that at
least we can see that this screenshot is
being captured okay
so uh let's go ahead and execute this
okay so now a screenshot should be
captured after it clicks on login and
we'll verify that by going to that
particular folder okay
in the scratch book
um you can see in that particular test
step that it is showing you in the
details where this particular screenshot
is captured right so you can copy the
path from here or if you know then you
can also go to that particular path in
the login info it will tell you a
screenshot was successfully created okay
so you can put these steps multiple
times at various other places where you
want to capture something right uh it
could be part of any requirement right
so here if I go I have got some other
screenshots but this one is the one
which I named it now screenshot you can
see there is a particular date time
right
and if I run this again it will capture
the same screenshot but with a different
name okay
so uh this seems to be useful but still
it doesn't actually uh solve any purpose
for me because I want to see where my
test step has failed right and I want to
capture something or
and I want to capture a screenshot of my
failure right so where it failed to do
something or verify something uh in the
application okay
so uh to do this uh there is an
automatic way you don't need to use any
modules or make any changes to your test
cases you can apply it at a project
level okay so for that we need to go to
Project settings
right and then we need to go to D box
and in this t-box there is something
called a logging and inside logging that
is screenshots okay
so here by default uh make screenshot on
failed test steps this will be uh
switched off but you can turn it on okay
and there are two options either on
detection failure or verification
failure I would suggest put it on the
verification failure because that's
where uh your tests will fail and you
want to see them in results what has
failed okay
again screenshot directory you can put
it anything I have put the same
directory where it can store and then
the image format right there are
different image formats you can choose
from I will choose PNG
and these are the three settings which
you need to do at a project level this
will be applicable everywhere okay
and now when we execute this test case
again and if it fails it is going to
capture a screenshot in that particular
folder okay
so let's go ahead and run this
okay now when I look at the scratch book
after this test case has been completed
uh you will see that our normal
screenshot has been taken as well
because we did not remove this step but
once this test case fails something has
changed now in the detail section you
can see there is a system.drawing dot
bitmap but it doesn't show me the
screenshot right so it is not possible
to see this and scratchbook you need to
run it in our execution list
so let's go ahead and do that I have
execution list folder here called demo
and I'm going to pull this screenshots
into this particular demo execution list
folder okay
so let's put this here and
we will name this as screenshots
okay down
so that's my execution list inside this
I have got my test case right
now let's go ahead and run this and
let's see if it now shows the actual
screenshot in our execution list results
okay so now in the login for you will
see that uh it is showing it as failed
the test case but the important thing uh
which we required is in the details
section now you can see
uh both uh the screenshots one which we
have taken it uh by a module and also uh
the failure test step right so the field
test step where it failed on the
verification part so it is going to take
a screenshot automatically right you
don't require any particular test step
or any changes
and you can extend this so this is part
of your debugging right so whenever a
test step fails you can then see where
it exactly field but uh this is not the
right this is not the right screenshot
and that is because I closed the window
uh even before or I came back to this
window uh before it took a particular
screenshot but let me run this again
quickly and I will show you the correct
screenshot right
okay so once the test case is completely
uh finished then only come to the
results section
or else you are going to get a different
kind of screenshot right like I did
so now uh coming to the latest execution
uh here you will see that now it has got
the correct screenshot here okay
so you can see it is the demo webshop
and uh now looking at the screenshot I
can find out where my test is exactly
filled right so it failed uh the login
was unsuccessful because of uh incorrect
email or password okay
so looking at that then I can go ahead
and fix my particular uh test case so
it's it's good in terms of debugging any
particular failures and the Tee Box take
screenshot module is good for any
particular screenshots which you want to
capture at any point of time okay so you
can use both hand in hand depending on
your scenario how you want to perform or
take screenshots while running your test
cases
so that's all for how you can take
screenshots uh in Tosca using different
ways one is a t-box module and one is a
system settings
foreign